<resources>

    <string name="app_name">Five Things to Save a Life</string>

    <string name="cpr">CPR (Cardio Pulmonary Resuscitation)</string>
    <string name="consciousChoking">Conscious Choking (Heimlich Maneuver)</string>
    <string name="bleeding">External Bleeding</string>
    <string name="drowning">Drowning</string>
    <string name="burns">Burns</string>

    <string name="emergencyNumberTitle">Emergency number</string>
    <string name="emergencyNumber911">911</string>

    <string name="title_activity_detail">Five Things to Save a Life</string>

    <string name="cprFirstInstruction">
        1. - Place the victim on his or her back. Make sure he or she is lying as flat as possible.
    </string>

    <string name="cprSecondInstruction">
        2. - Push hard, push fast in the middle of the chest at least 2 inches (5 centimeters) deep and at least 100 compressions per minute.
    </string>

    <string name="cprThirdInstruction">
        3. - Tilt the head back and lift the chin up.\n
        - Pinch the nose shut then make a complete seal over the person’s mouth.\n
        - Blow in for about 1 second to make the chest clearly rise.\n
        - Give rescue breaths, one after the other.\n\nNote: If chest does not rise with rescue breaths, retilt the head and give another rescue breath.
    </string>

    <string name="cprFourthInstruction">
        4. - Continue cycles of CPR. Do not stop CPR except in one of these situations:\n
        - You find an obvious sign of life, such as breathing.\n
        - An AED (Automated External Defibrillator) is ready to use.\n
        - Another trained responder or EMS personnel take over.\n
        - You are too exhausted to continue.\n
        - The scene becomes unsafe.
    </string>

    <string name="consciousChokingFirstInstruction">
        1. - Give 5 back blows. Bend the person forward at the waist and give 5 back blows between the shoulder blades with the heel of one hand.
    </string>

    <string name="consciousChokingSecondInstruction">
        2. - Give 5 abdominal thrusts (Heimlich maneuver).\n
        - Place a fist with the thumb side against the middle of the person’s abdomen, just above the navel.\n
        - Cover your fist with your other hand.\n
        - Give 5 quick, upward abdominal thrusts.
    </string>

    <string name="consciousChokingThirdInstruction">
        3. - Continue sets of 5 back blows and 5 abdominal thrusts until the:\n
        - Object is forced out.\n
        - Person can cough forcefully or breathe.\n
        - Person becomes unconscious.
    </string>

    <string name="bleedingFirstInstruction">
        1. - Cover the wound with a sterile dressing.
    </string>

    <string name="bleedingSecondInstruction">
        2. - Apply direct pressure until bleeding stops.
    </string>

    <string name="bleedingThirdInstruction">
        3. - Cover the dressing with bandage. Check for circulation beyond the injury (check for feeling, warmth and color).
    </string>

    <string name="burnsFirstInstruction">
        1. - Remove from source of burn.
    </string>

    <string name="burnsSecondInstruction">
        2. - Cool the burn with cold running water at least until pain is relieved.
    </string>

    <string name="burnsThirdInstruction">
        3. - Cover loosely with sterile dressing and care for shock.
    </string>

    <string name="drowningFirstInstruction">
        1. - Take the person out of water, look to see if the person’s chest is moving and check the person’s pulse for 10 seconds.
    </string>

    <string name="drowningSecondInstruction">
        2. - If the person can’t breath start CPR (Cardio Pulmonary Resuscitation), see CPR section for instructions.
    </string>
</resources>
